yeah i went a little bit overboard with
the barge box mystery hunt prize pool so
it is all done and the value now is
around fourteen hundred one thousand
four hundred diamonds worth of value in
the shulker boxes it's quite insane we
still haven't started the quest because
along with this quest i actually want to
upgrade the barge so i've got a couple
of boxes full of goodies and that's one
of the first things that i wanted to do
in today's episode of hermitcraft it is
a very very busy day today like it's
it's difficult to fly and load anything
in this is what happens when you have a
lot of people i can't see anything this
is terrifying maybe maybe right now
isn't the best time to do much building
it's even taking me a while to get
through portals so
this iteration of the barge has been
here for quite some time who broke a
fence so i have been designing this a
little bit off camera and i've got
myself a bunch of materials to try and
build this up however this is a mammoth
task like really mammoth the design that
i have in mind basically means tearing
all of this down or at least the top
half
and starting all over again
so
before we hello
the heck is this
giant
laser beam
my goodness
seriously
the heap are going insane
i mean way to look not look like the bad
guy at least it's solar paneled right
building a giant doomsday laser is like
the most super villain thing i can think
of it's in like all of the spy movies
but it's solar powered and therefore
very environmentally friendly
i've got mixed emotions about this but
oh my goodness it looks so cool look at
this it's got scar written all over it
the builds out of this thing have been
amazing that kind of reminds me that i
haven't actually
finished
putting much mycelium anywhere to be
honest with you i started a little bit
at the end of last episode but i did not
continue
so i yeah i better yeah i better get
back to putting some uh
some mycelium
back in this place i actually just want
to make sure that i've got enough
mycelium before i start this project
there's no point starting unless i've
got it all now we got out of there with
a bunch of these shulker boxes right we
got out of the hep hq
with a whole lot of this okay there's a
mixture of junk shulker boxes in here in
fact i think there's even more in these
boxes over here
our storage system is an enormous mess
yeah this thing is a giant mess
did i hear an explosion
i think i hear an explosion what is
going on
ice
is that above me
where is that coming for i think it's
coming from this direction
yeah it
okay
the heck
what is going on
is there something in decked out that's
like no is someone making like a blow up
minigame or something oh
oh wait
oh
dude
no
what
no way mambo
what's mumbo doing with scar are they
gonna
are they gonna break in
did they know i'm here they might have
seen my name tag how have i only just
seen their name tags
i'm not even sure if they might go over
me
i'm not sure if they're even gonna break
in you know okay they're gonna break in
okay okay okay
oh my goodness panic panic panic
emergency meeting oh that's including me
panic panic
they found us
grab stuff
get
the mycelium
get them out
they're over there
oh my goodness
get the source block
red alert
it just
said hi
oh no
no get the valuables storage room
storage room storage room
forget forget the iron blocks
get the mycelium out of here
no
storage room people
storage room
get out of here oh my man
what are we gonna
get out okay okay okay
evacuate
get out of here get out of here
the base
how did they know where we were
that did someone give all the did
someone give the chords away oh my
goodness no
no no no no no
someone must have been someone
must have given us away there's no other
explanation someone was careless
someone was really careless someone did
a bad cut or
left some coordinates in how they knew
exactly where we were they would they
they tunneled right directly into us i
don't i don't even know what to do
only two of us got out oh man i'm just
i'm telling them i'm on discord hello
impulse oh my goodness what just
happened dude
someone was careless someone must have
given us away no
no i think we were all pretty good i
never exposed the coordinates or
anything they came in through the roof
there was like tnt going on yeah like
remember the vault event i just saw an
operation
uh dudes we should have put some sort of
plan in place for this eventuality
because we're all running around like
idiots
we're really lucky we actually got all
the myself where are you guys
i got a little bit i barely got any of
it out of there
i've got i've got a lot of it i managed
to get a lot of it out of there i got
like one shocker only excellent
right there xp's here i mean i don't
want to miss anyone this probably only
applies to me but i just saw like an
apparition of xb floating through the
air it was really weird um okay
uh can we all let's all reconvene at the
town hall outside town hall well this
isn't where i wanted to have a meeting
actually i i know a place where they
probably wouldn't expect us to have a
meeting because i i helped build it ages
ago but actually
everyone fly up with me there's a
there's a little secret room that no one
knows about
just behind the town hall so hold on let
me open this up for you
there's a little secret room in here
this is where we're gonna have our
meeting
there he goes the secret room behind the
town hall okay it's a little tip
everyone hold shift oh good idea here we
go okay
right
not good
not good i mean it was only a matter of
time to be fair i'm surprised it took
them this long but we officially i mean
the only commodity the only valuable
thing about that base was the fact that
it was secret
[Laughter]
yeah yeah i i can't believe they found
it
did somebody leak the coordinates or
something no i don't think so i didn't
i'm pretty sure i know your eyes would
stick to me
i'm not gonna like everyone literally
did look at you
so from here we actually managed to get
out with some mycelium i've got shulker
boxes of the stuff still
so we got we got out of there with the
good stuff however
i'm pretty sure we're gonna need a new
base and i'm thinking yes this time we
we kind of will collaborate on it and
build it above ground kind of like the
hep has okay oh yeah yeah very cool uh
keeping it secret was a lot of energy
it was
oh i had to kill myself so many times
just to enter that place
and i mean you guys built the base twice
yeah
yeah yeah okay so from here we'll hide
the mycelium
and we'll get we'll get designing on a
on a second base an above ground base
technically this would be like the third
base this will be the third base
that we would have got away with the two
if it wasn't for those darn
hip kids those meddling a hip before
that does everyone wanna give me a hand
turning the shopping district into
mycelium because that would that would
be
that would be really that would be
really helpful actually
can do yeah we'll get something out of
this that that way we don't need to hide
this my scene we don't need to store it
we can just uh yeah we can just get it
out there and do what we plan to do in
the first place
well we have managed to do it half the
shopping district
is covered in mycelium and i think we
should all agree
not to acknowledge that it actually
doesn't look better
i think we all just need to take a
second
to just you know take it in
and tell ourselves
okay maybe it doesn't look better but
it's about sending a message we all we
all acknowledge that it definitely
doesn't look better as mycelium than
grass
but we all agree not to talk about it
now that our base has been discovered by
hip
i think it's time to show you where the
actual entrance was all this time all of
the bamboozling all of the mind games
and brain games we've been doing and
messing with everybody
there was a whole lot of shenanigans
going on in fact it's scott's still
online i'm gonna message him and i'm
gonna show you and him exactly where the
entrance is
so i've asked him want to see the
entrance to the base
there he is
where are you
i found the local transportation
first of all
i'm not even gonna ask never mind um
yeah so i'll i'll do a little bit of a
backtrack i'll explain what's going on
because i need some explanations from
you straight away okay i wanna know
first and foremost
how did you find our base who messed up
how did you find out
oh no it was my brilliance what do you
mean from from all my strip mining oh
you did you didn't know where the base
was at all no you you didn't know i've
been strip mining the entire shopping
district huh yeah and then i got the
enlisted the help of um sir odiah here
and he made me these little boring
machines finally because obviously i saw
i saw mumbo then i was super confused
okay
so
how long have you been strip mining
under the shopping district
uh
almost two weeks
is that what the laser is
oh yeah the definitely not evil laser
yeah i said that earlier i was like this
looks so evil okay
right i thought someone had given away
the
coordinates somehow or messed up by
showing the entrance no you just did it
by trial and error systematically made
your way through this oh my gosh dude i
i it's just nice to be out of those
caves i'll be honest with you also i
found ancient hermitcraft builds that
nobody ever put in their videos under
there i've seen i have seen some weird
things down in the bowels of the
shopping district well okay first of all
congratulations point to hep you've you
discovered the base our first point and
we are now
baseless the whole team is baseless so
you know actually
the only thing that the base was good
for was being secret and now that it's
not secret you know you can have it it's
yours it's your base now you can pepify
it turn it into a hep storage unit i
don't care it's ruined but
would you like to see where the
yeah i'll show you i'll show you do you
want to see where the entrance has been
this whole time
well can i can i just give you my one of
my guesses yeah go on i walked into odia
over here and i pushed and pulled every
lever there possibly could because i
just figured being mumbo the
head of the of the resistance
dude i did i did everything i did them
all i i turned everything like
i've never been in here right come on
i'll show you where it is it's
you're gonna you're gonna really kick
yourself
where are we going we go it's here it
was here the whole time it's right here
under stresses stress monsters tree the
reason stress accidentally found our
base and joining the resistance is
because the entrance
is literally right here you open this
shulker box
and you fall in
you have to saw this and thought it was
like her extra storage one day i was
like well that's peculiar
this holds okay well apparently it's
scar proof dude
stand on top of it there we go
this is the real
base and it was there the whole time
and you know people had actually figured
out where we were because of bedrock and
stuff but we just like pretended like
they didn't for the i think it's now 205
emails that i've received on the base
locations i haven't read any of them so
everyone who sent it i appreciate it but
i did not want to get spoiled good but i
do appreciate you taking the time that's
why we also don't watch each other's
videos as well because it spoils too
much yeah so sorry about the vault
wait i actually want to go and have a
look at this
look at the dead face
right dude that looks it's like
something out of a movie
that is amazing
right okay so also somehow this boring
machine got lined up absolutely perfect
so it went straight down the middle of
this place
nicely done it's my unintentional
brilliance so wait this is where you've
been stripped mine oh bro
oh bro you have been strip mining
there's also
a lot of these boreholes and other areas
everywhere basically has been strip
mined right so um congratulations you've
got yourself one
one resistance headquarters this is all
yours now
two technically we found the fake one
you found the fake one as well okay so
my my audience don't actually know this
but hilariously the fake base is
literally right next to this one it's
like maybe 20 blocks that direction or
that direction i'm not sure so yeah the
it's really funny okay well enjoy your
new base
uh we're gonna make we'll make a new
base i guess all right well then
we'll see you in the in the fields you
won't you won't well you won't need to
find you might need to look for this one
because it'll just it'll just be out
there oh really well then i'll be
looking forward to seeing it all right
goodbye brother explorer bye have a
great day
have a good day
bye
that was literally the ultimate
distraction of distractions well we got
our task done
we have covered the shopping district in
mycelium but now it's time to get back
to what we actually planned on doing
upgrading the barge so the first thing
we need to do is actually take it down
even though it's going to be pretty much
the same design palette and block types
because the design is changing even if
it's only slightly i've got to take out
this entire section
so let the demolishing begin
[Music]
[Applause]
so i've stripped back the barge to a
more minimalist look
i actually forgot that i had to take out
the existing glass this is all that's
going to remain of the original design
of the barge well it's going to look
almost identical but you know when you
upgrade stuff you've got to change out
the block palette and my goodness so
this is this is kind of it like this is
what the barge looks like and actually
feels exactly the same on the inside
it's just you know more accessible
so now i just wanted to sort of
appreciate how it looked
before i actually started building
because it took me over an hour just to
remove the stuff you know why isn't
glass instant mine it's really annoying
i've got haste 2 here and glass is one
of the most painful things to break
so now that that's out the way let's get
started on the proper build of the barge
upgrade three
what's the equivalent of electric
boogaloo for three
i think there is one all right well
let's go anyway i mean
a little bit less
rhymey but let's go
check it out everyone
this is the new and upgraded barge it's
looking a little bit dare i say it
gothic because of all the spikes that i
added on it it's looking majorly
victorian and like a proper mansion now
but
a mansion green house if i can say that
if it
that is the closest thing i can think of
so what i've done here the design is
pretty simple i've replicated this layer
and just basically pushed everything
upwards added some spikes and what it's
done is given it a bunch of height
and it's still maintained the fact that
it's a barge so you can see i've still
got the barge layer here it's still
floating on water but then i've also put
a layer here just to remind everyone
that we are still a giant barge this is
a monstrosity amalgamation of styles and
build palette i don't know it's bit odd
and very unique i really like this build
there's nothing quite like it and i also
managed to keep the fact that you can
fly in that's really important to me so
on the inside things seem a lot darker
just because i've changed it out for
gray glass instead of light gray glass
and i've added in the staircase to get
upstairs and as you can see
there's absolutely zero stock here
i'm not entirely sure what stock i'm
gonna put in here i was thinking about
selling stuff
by the box i think that's a really good
slogan
green's barge company buy the box and it
could even be like buy the box
you see i think that's a really good
slogan and then i can sell stuff by the
box although that's a
crazy amount of grinding i'm not sure if
i will
but here's the here's what's really
weird about this whole build right when
i fly up and sort of have like a higher
scene over here it doesn't actually look
like it's changed that much all i've
really done is brought the building in
the same scale with its surroundings
basically what prompted this was the
builds all around here were looking so
cool and so insane that the barge was
feeling a little bit small and maybe a
bit inadequate but now it's a bit bigger
a bit more complex it looks way more at
home
now this leads me to my next thing i was
wondering how on earth
do i upgrade this again
and i'm not sure that i really want to
go higher i must admit six hours of
building that was painful it really was
and i was wondering if maybe i could
purchase some of the older shops around
here that don't look like they're going
to get an upgrade so maybe i'll put an
offer in
and see if the other hermits are willing
to sell their old shops or maybe move
them i'm not sure because if i could get
this land here that would be amazing for
the barge it could it could expand out
this way so what i'm gonna do is put a
quick offer in and see if they're
interested in selling interested in
selling this space offer is in the chest
so i'm thinking a stack of diamonds
plus
a little bit more to sweeten the deal i
mean that makes it look like there's so
much more diamonds than there are
but that would be a pretty good offer i
feel to part with this space they're not
mega complicated builds it'll probably
be half an hour so i think that's a
pretty decent deal
and i'm not sure how often they sell
stuff i mean i know i bought tridents
from here
but maybe they're more because you see
shops can be a bit of a hassle to keep
up so maybe they'll be interested maybe
they're not i'm not forcing them at all
but let's just see if they will be
interested in this we're trying to buy
out the entire shopping district i'll
also do the tnt shop as well in fact
jevin owns this shop and i don't think
he's ever restocked it so he may end up
just being finished with it and may end
up actually just taking my offer anyways
and just give me the space and then i
can also sell tnt in the barge
exclusively that would be pretty cool so
the barge has the option to expand
in many directions if i'm able to secure
this land and that would be pretty cool
for the future of this amazing shop that
i really really like in fact i like this
so much i'm actually considering moving
this into season eight as a different
like a rebrand maybe barge curl or
something
not entirely sure i mean i know i just
said season eight but season eight is a
really long time away it's just i know
the thought has occurred to me that kind
of takes care of the shop now i need to
make the big quest
that will be over the next couple of
episodes but i have got some pretty cool
ideas for how this can go down this is a
multiple stage thing that i have to do
in the background but i must admit the
mycelium war is kind of taking most of
my time now we need to choose a spot
for our base now i've been thinking the
only real logical spot that we can take
is off the coast because there is
actually just no space for a huge huge
mycelium hq they've had to build off map
over there the hep the hep had to build
a big tower there so i'm thinking we're
probably going to need to claim
a little bit of offshore land here
now i'm definitely going to need help
this is the mycelium
hq
humble beginnings this three by three
space
i need to get designing on a
headquarters and i think
that's probably
going to have to be the end of the
episode there's been an awful lot that's
happened in this episode
we officially lost the mycelium hq we
have transformed the shopping district
and we've had a chat with scar and we
upgraded the barge most importantly look
at this build i'm so happy with it
handsome shop so all there is left to
say thank you very much for watching and
i shall see you in the next video
good bye